Oscar Castro

Full Stack Web Developer

abla

oscar.a.castro818@gmail.com



210-849-6794



LinkedIn/oscar-ct



GitHub/oscar-ct



https://oscar-ct.github.io/

Ambitious Software Developer with a background in asset, account, and contract management as a former procurement specialist. Merging a passion for programming to create intuitive, useful, and efficient web applications in fast-paced teams with JavaScript and Java frameworks that aid in user experience and accessibility.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Support Desk - repo

Need IT support for your favorite electronics? Support desk is here to help. Built on the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS), users can login/signup, submit support tickets with full CRUD functionality, and view ticket notes made by the user and Support Specialist. Supported by Redux Toolkit for state handling and Mongoose for object modeling. Styling is finished with Bootstrap 5.

Dream Cars - repo / demo

Looking to rent or buy your dream car? Or maybe you want to make some money selling/renting your vehicles? Dream Car has you covered. Utilizing Create React App, Firebase, Firestore, and Mapbox API; users can create an account, create car listings with full CRUD functionality, upload images, view maps, and much more. Styling is finished with TailwindCSS/daisyui.

React Films - repo / demo

Whether you love a movie and want to remember it, or you are looking for a new film to watch, React Films can help. Utilizing CRA, Context API, and OMDb API, users can search from thousands of movie titles and save/share their favorites films. Styling is modern and sleek, built with TailwindCSS/daisyui.

Gamer Haven - repo

A gaming social media app built by a team of 5, implementing Agile and Scrum methods. Users can create accounts, personalize their profile, search games, follow users, create posts, comment, and more. Backend is built with Java Spring Boot and MySQL. Frontend is built with Thymeleaf, jQuery, JavaScript, Filestack, and RAWG API. Styling is finished with Bootstrap 5.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Personal Shopper / Walmart Dec 2022 - Present / San Antonio, TX

> Fulfill customer orders by reviewing, locating, preparing, and packaging merchandise Procurement Specialist / Cudd Energy Services

Mar 2016 - Mar 2020 / San Antonio, TX

- > Responsible for procurement of approx. \$250,000+ of monthly inventory
- > Participated in meetings and video conferences with existing or new vendors to establish and sustain healthy vendor relationships
- > Managed a comprehensive district wide monthly expense analysis database and reporting for key stakeholders
- > Streamlined buying processes, procedures, and negotiated pricing of goods/services with suppliers to execute daily purchase order numbers
- > Prepared and executed monthly company credit card expense reports
- > Worked closely with Department Manager to communicate high priority purchases

Asset Coordinator / Cudd Energy Services Feb 2014 - Mar 2016 / San Antonio, TX

- > Cross-trained with Lead Buyer to develop procurement experience for promotion
- > Managed the annual physical asset inventory to increase accountability and reduce loss of 5,000+ assets
- > Prepared asset disposal documents to facilitate the sale and coordination of disposed company assets
- > Developed and improved high-dollar asset record keeping databases with MS excel

SKILLS

Frontend

JavaScript ES6

ReactJS - Redux

CSS3 - HTML5 -

TailwindCSS - Bootstrap

Backend

Java SE - Java EE (Servlets, JSP/JSTL)

NodeJS - Express -Mongoose - Spring Boot (Thymeleaf)

MySQL - MongoDB - Firebase

Technical

Git + GitHub, Agile Scrum Methodology, MVC Design, Object Oriented Programming, Database Design, Test-Driven Development, Paired Programming

EDUCATION

Codeup

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022 / San Antonio, TX

Certificate of Completion

A fully immersive, projectbased, in-person 22-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development.